<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Home</title>
 <link href="http://josephjustin.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://josephjustin.com"/>
 <updated>2012-05-31T10:23:32+05:30</updated>
 <id>http://josephjustin.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Justin Joseph</name>
   <email>justin@josephjustin.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Justin Profile</title>
   <link href="http://josephjustin.com/2012/05/31/justin-profile"/>
   <updated>2012-05-31T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://josephjustin.com/2012/05/31/justin-profile</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Email: justin@josephjustin.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Justin Joseph&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='profile'&gt;Profile&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linux Systems Engineer with 8 years experience on networking in Linux and C system programming on Linux. Computer science and engineering graduate(B.Tech), worked extensively on Linux with practical knowledge of Linux TCP/IP networking stack, networking applications and C programming on Linux. Experience in networking capabilities of linux including Netfilter framework and applications implementing features like IDS/IPS, VRRP, IPSec VPN etc. Experience in tool chain building and programming microcontroller. Proficient in using development tools on linux including gcc, gdb, diff, make, gprof, svn etc. Experience in writing device drivers for linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='technical_skills'&gt;Technical Skills&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Operating System : System Programming skills on Linux – knowledge of system calls, IPC mechanisms (shared memory, semaphores), POSIX threads, device driver writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Programming Languages : Skilled in C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unix Tools: Make, Diff, Patch, gdb, gprof, svn, git-svn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microcontroller: ATMEL ATMega8.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Networking: TCP/IP Networking stack and applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='work_experience_8_years'&gt;Work Experience (8 years)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worked in challenging roles at startups like Elina Networks Pvt Ltd, Bangalore (Sr. R&amp;amp;D Engineer) ,Solidcore Techsoft, New Delhi (Trainee Software Engineer). Intel Bangalore(contracted in role of Linux Consultant), Wipro Technologies (Senior consultant).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='academic_qualification'&gt;Academic Qualification&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science &amp;amp; Engineering, from MES College of Engineering, Kuttipuram, under University Of Calicut (1999-2003).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='roles_and_achievements'&gt;Roles and Achievements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Senior Consultant working at Intel in the Low Power IA(Power and Performance) team, I was responsible for providing solutions aiding in Power and Performance improvements for Meego O.S running on Intel Medfield platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Sr. R&amp;amp;D Engineer working at Elina Networks(product start-up company), I was responsible for implementing network functionality on Elina router/firewall. Being part of a technology start up which incubated at IIM Bangalore, I worked on a broad range of requirements in a tight schedule. Was responsible in adhering to short release cycles targeting multiple features thereby enabling Elina to meet new client requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My career involved usage of Open source software and collaboration with the Open source community at large. Worked with different Open source communities in India and is the founder member of FSMK www.fsmk.org and computerclub.in http://computerclub.in/ComputerClubIndiaAtFossIn2009&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='projects_summary'&gt;Projects Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id='isdb_stack_implementationintegration_with_bcm7424'&gt;ISDB stack implementation/integration with BCM7424&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worked on developing and integrating Wipro ISDB-T/S stack with Broadcom set-top box platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contribution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maintained the abstraction layer used by all the ISDB layers for system services (sys calls), IPC related tasks(mutex, semaphores, message queues etc..). Wrote the build system for integrating different ISDB layers like hardware abstraction layer, browser markup language layer, OS Synchronization layer, ISDB middle ware. Implemented the persistent storage component(part of the Hardware abstraction layer). Implemented BML layer APIs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology Skills&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proficiency in Linux systems programming environment. Proficiency in maintaining large code base. Understanding of Linux build system(Makefiles).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='intel_low_power_ia_power_and_performance_team'&gt;Intel low power IA (power and Performance team)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worked local on-site at Intel in the Power and Performance team. Worked on developing tools and enabling Performance measurements/Optimizations on Meego mobile platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contribution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wrote code for SFI table parser, glibc profiler, made Linux kernel modifications for enabling Performance benchmarking on Medfield Intel Mobile platform at 1.6Ghz freq. Analyzed glibc memory routine throughputs which led to performance improvement of strcpy function on Meego/Medfield. Provided solution for compiling Nokia compiler performance suite for Meego/Medfield platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology Skills&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Proficiency in Linux systems programming environment. CPUfreq Linux Kernel subsystem, C programming, Intel SFI Specification. Linux timer mechanism. Linux Driver development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='routerfirewall_functionality'&gt;Router/Firewall functionality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Network functionality implementation for Elina Router/Firewall&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contribution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Implemented various network functionalities, including Snort based IDS/IPS, OpenSwan based IPSec VPN, Bind based DNS, c-icap based ICAP functionality, Frox FTP Proxy, vsftp based FTP Server, Netfilter/Iptables and Shorewall based firewall, Inspector based chat proxy, Keepalive based VRRP support, QoS, ISDN etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provided Patches and bug reports to the Shoreline Firewall project (www.shorewall.net ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology Skills&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TCP/IP Networking on Linux, C programming, Networking programs on Linux.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='router_hardware_functionality_check'&gt;Router hardware functionality Check&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hardware Program Suite to analyze the ENPAQ 2105 series router&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contribution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designed and implemented the hardware suite (manufacturing tests) for ENPAQ 2105 series router. The suite tested all the hardware on the IBase IB798 SBC used by the router to function. C program binaries are invoked to test the LED’s, RTL network card (4 Ethernet ports), mouse, parallel port, serial port, sensors, hard disk, flash disk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology Skills&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linux systems programming. C programming, Ibase SBC Board specification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='hdlc_driver_development'&gt;HDLC Driver development.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HDLC driver for Serocco PEB 20525 HDLC/PPP mini PCI card&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contribution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wrote Linux kernel (V 2.6) driver for SEROCCO-H PEB20525 HDLC/PPP mini PCI card. The driver enabled leased line connectivity for ENPAQ 2105 routers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology Skills&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linux Network Driver development. C programming. Understanding hardware (SEROCCO-H PEB20525) specifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='vpd_programmer'&gt;VPD Programmer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Realtek RTL8139 VPD(Vital Private Data) Programmer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contribution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designed and Implemented the RTL EEPROM programmer for storing Elina Serial number and other details on the RTL8139 EEPROM VPD. There are read/write/dump options. The program can write serial numbers or read them or dump the VPD contents on terminal. The code was modification and extension of the rtl8139-diag GPL code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology Skills&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linux systems programming. C programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LED and Watchdog timer programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Programmed the LED’s and Watchdog timer on the IBase IB798&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contribution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The LED’s on the IBase IB798, the LED’s were used to display WAN, STATUS, FAIL on the ENPAQ 2105 router. Init scripts are used as wrapper for the LED program to control the LED’s and they indicate the status of the router. Programmed the WDT on the W83697HF Winbound chip on the IBase board. The program is invoked by init script and would reset the processor in case the Linux kernel stalls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology Skills&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linux systems programming. C programming. Bash scripting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='philips_i2c_protocol'&gt;Philips I2C Protocol&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Implementing Phillips I2C protocol&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contribution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project involved data acquisition with the ATMega8 micro and storing the same on 24C04 SEEPROM. The SEEPROM communicates using the I2C protocol, and the ATMega end of the protocol was implemented in C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology Skills&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microcontroller GPIO Programming, I2C protocol specification. C Programming. Microcontroller Tool chain building on Linux(Cross compiler, Assembler). Parallel Port based microcontroller programmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id='hobby_kit_development'&gt;Hobby Kit Development&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ATMega8 microcontroller based hobby kit (Similar to Arduino)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contribution&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developed Hobby kit based on ATMega8 Microcontroller and Linux based Opensource tool chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology Skills&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Linux systems programming. C programming. Tool chain building. Assembling hardware programmer.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>